Sois
Le feu et la terre
炎と大地
L'eau et la poussière
水と塵
Héros malgré toi
望まないヒーロー･･･
Vois
La légende s'écrire
伝説は記され
L'histoire se construire
歴史は創られる
L'avenir est notre aventure
未来は私たちの冒険だ
Fais
Vivre la lumière
陽光に命が宿り
Parler les éclairs
雷鳴は語りかける
La magie entre tes mains
魔法は君の手の中に
Pars
Suive ton chemin
自らの道を進め
Et regarde ton futur
そして見よ
未来を
L'aventure
冒険を
Ta lumière guider ton destin
光が導く運命を
16-The Cursed Fountain
ミﾞ、ミﾞスﾞゥゥ...
なんでいつもこういう状況に陥っちゃうわけ？
寄り道してばかりだからよ
時間が豊富にあるなら、弱きを助け強きをくじくのもいいけどね
ああ、でも俺たちはヒーローだ。
弱いものを助けるのはヒーローの義務だぜ
その通りだよパンパン、ヒーローは世界を良くするためにいるんだ
気持ちはわかるわ。でも悲劇的な話なんてそこら中に溢れてるのよ
何をすべきか考えなきゃ。最優先なのはなに？
わからん･･･何も考えられん･･･脳みそこんがりじゃ
ユーゴ、答えて！
最優先か･･･
うーん、シノノメのドフスを見つけることかな
Well it doesn't look like it.ええ、順調とは言えないわ
出発してから数週間経つけど、まだ半分も来てないのよ
この調子じゃあと数週間はかかるわ
アダマイのことも考えてあげて
できる限り早く戻るって約束したでしょう
みんながあなたの冒険に心血を注いでるのよ
それでもあなたが世界中の苦しみを解決したいっていうなら
好きにすればいいわ
でもよければ、この任務が終わってからにしない？
僕･･･僕は･･･
わかったよ、エヴァ。これからは任務に集中する
あそこを見て！
地図に載ってるオアシスだわ！
水だ！！
あっちじゃ！水の流れる音が聞こえるぞ
ああ、あっちだ！入り口がある
ちょっと！置いていかないでよ！
これだよ、正にパラダイスだぜ
パンパン、認めるのは癪じゃがそうとしか言いようがないな･･･
水だーーー！！！
立ち去れ、見知らぬものたちよ
私はボードガン、何人たりともこの泉の水を飲ませるわけにはいかない
なんだって？
なんで飲んじゃだめなんだ
見逃してくれんかのぅ。ワシらはのどが渇いて死にそうなんじゃ
確かにここは凄まじく暑いからな
だが申し訳ない。飲ませるわけにはいかんのだ
Don't think I'll drink to that.
あのぉ、なんで飲んじゃだめなんですか？
なぜ飲んではいけないか、だと？
それは･･･
絶対に飲んではいけないからだ！
それじゃあちょっと納得はできんのう！若造！
ああ、俺もリュエルと同感だぜ
ダメーー！
ん？
やめて、お願いだから
彼が失礼を。悪い人ではないのです
ただ･･･彼自身、ここで何をしているのかわからないのです
お水なら少しあります
どうぞ、お好きなだけ飲んでください
ありがとう、お嬢さん
女性と子供が先よ！
立ち去れ、見知らぬものよ。
私はボードガン、何人――
ええ、ボードガン、わかってるわ。泉に用があって来たんじゃないのよ
食べ物を持ってきたの
食べ物？
なんて親切な。ありがとう、お嬢さん
今日は、ドライフルーツとシリアル、デザートにカルーガも
素晴らしい。カルーガは好物なんだ。良くわかったね
毎日来てるからね、ボードガン･･･
そうなのか？ところで･･･君の名前は？
アリア･･･
私はアリアよ
アリア？素敵な名前だ
じゃあ、ありがとう、アリア
また明日ね、ボードガン･･･
一緒にいらっしゃいますか？
私の村はここからそれほど離れていないのです
大したおもてなしもできませんけど･･･
村の泉は･･･あちらです
この辺りは旅人もほとんど訪れないのです
しばらくこちらで外の話を聞かせてくださるとうれしいわ
そうしたいのはやまやまだけれど、長い旅の途中なのよ
あまり長居はできないの
せめて食べ物だけでも持っていってください
南海岸への道は厳しいわ
砂漠を横断するには、十分な食料が必要です
うん！親切にありがとう！
アマリア、私はユーゴと行ってくるから、彼らをよろしく
じゃあまた後で
こら！老人には優しくせんか！
ぼくはボードガン！この泉を守ってる！あっちへいけ！
坊主、お情けをかけて今回は許してやろう
もう許さんぞ！
いいかげんにしなさい！
すぐにやめなさい！
ごめんなさいね、旅の方。躾がなってなくて
食事をしたいなら、ローカの宿があるわ。ちょうど行くところだったの
怒られる前におうちに帰りなさい！
その態度はなに！？今すぐあっちへ行きなさい！！
I think we've stumbled upon a “village de fous”.
干し肉を少し入れましょう、おかずにいいわ
なぜボードガンは泉を守っているの？
何か特別な事情でもあるの？
呪いなの
呪い？
これは長くて悲しいお話
ボードガンは私の恋人なの
私たちはみな、オグレストの混沌で飲み込まれてしまった島から来たの
ボードガンは放棄された村の話を聞きつけてきて
環境は厳しく、他から隔絶された土地だけれど
私たちは新しく住処を見つけることが何より重要だった
彼はその場所を見つけて村を再建するため、
遠征隊を率いて行ったわ
でも２週間経っても音沙汰がなく、私たちは彼らを探すことにしたの
仲間は誰も見当たらず、ボードガンただ一人が残っていたわ
呪われた泉のところよ
彼は半ば狂ってしまっていた
彼は記憶を失っていて、私のこともわからなくなっていた
何が起きたかはわからないけれど、
私の愛が間違っていたとは思わないわ
彼は泉を守ろうとしてる。
あの泉が原因のひとつに違いないって確信してるの
それ以来ずっと、毎日食事を運んだりとか、お世話をしているの
彼の記憶が戻ることを願って
村の人は、私が絶望しておかしくなっちゃったと思ってる
でも必要とされる限りは待ち続けるつもりよ
私は･･･彼を見捨てないわ
記憶を取り戻すいい方法があるはずだよ･･･僕らが手伝うよ！
ユーゴ･･･
うん、エヴァ
僕･･･
ごめんアリア、僕ら緊急の任務の途中なんだ
でも戻ってきて手伝うよ、約束する
だよね、エヴァ？
アリアは可愛いけど、私に言わせればちょっとおばかさんね
私だったら、ボードガンみたいな野蛮な男、
そばに置いておくのは嫌だわ
I would've run off long ago to see if the grass was greener elsewhere.
What were they thinking, burrowing in such a godforsaken place?
子供たちもおかしくなってしもうたんじゃ
俺は彼女の気持ちがわかるぜ。恋は時に人を愚かにするものさ
な？エヴァ
いいえ、違うわ！
え、歩きたくないのか？俺に運んで欲しいってことか？
いいえ、違うわ･･･彼らをこのままにはしておけない。戻りましょう
何を言ってるんだ？
戻る？なぜ？なにか忘れ物でもしたの？
ありがとう、エヴァ
どういうことか説明してくれんかの？
I suppose you have done some research...
Yes, but we didn't find anything. Only Bordegann is left.
The villagers that accompanied him disappeared without a trace.
That cursed fountain's the one to blame, that's for sure.
But as I told you, we don't know if it's the water or the place that's cursed.
Well then we're going to study it stone by stone, there's bound to be a clue.
What kind of clue are we looking for?
Anything that looks magical. A gemstone, runes, a stele.
You're forgetting something...
Bordegann.
He won't let you get near the fountain.
Yeah. We've already tried several times, we never succeeded.
They're right. Bordegann is too strong. It's a lost cause.
Well it just so happens that we're specialists in lost causes.
Yeah! That's even how you recognize heroes.
Get back, stranger! My name is Bordegann and I protect--
I know, Bordegann, I know, I'm not interested in the fountain, I'm just bringing you something to eat.
Something to eat?
...and your favorite dessert: a calouga.
A calouga!
Are you ready?
Yeah! Ready to fight!
Grovy! The point is not to fight him, but to immobilize him and find some clues.
Oh, come on, I was just kidding.
Here we go!
What?!
What in the...
Your turn, guys!
We've got to check every nook and cranny.
What?!
What in the...
I'm really sorry, Bordegann.
No! The fountain! You must not get near it!
Villains! You will taste my wrath!
He's a tough one, that's for sure.
Say, Eva. Couldn't I use my sword? Just a little bit, to see if...
Grovy, no!
Well, at least tomorrow he'll have forgotten everything.
Well, we'll try something else.
Marriage?
Yes, our marriage.
Come on, hurry up, the mayor is waiting for us.
Yes, miss! Err... Alia!
One moment, I'm going to find my spear.
Uh, haven't I forgotten something? Now what was it again?
Come on, Bordegann! We're going to be late!
Oh yeah!
Get back, stranger, nobody must get near this fountain!
Well, Grovy, what was your plan again?
Oh! A calouga!
This is how my master got me out of a well that I had hidden in to sulk.
He's biting! He's biting, come help!
It's a big one, a real big one!
All together!
Well, Yugo, what was your idea again?
...and your favorite dessert: a calouga!
My favorite? Really? But... but how do you know that?
Oh it's a very long story, but I can tell you about it, if you wish.
With pleasure, stranger. I love stories.
At least... I-I think I do.
Ruel can talk for whole days without stopping.
A treasure like you've never seen!
Kamas by the hundreds, by the thousands! Ha, I believed I was in Enutrof's heaven.
Alas, yeah, alas...
...managed to steal from me. Such boldness!
Luckily, they were lead by a boss as ugly and stupid as my great-grandfather.
I say luckily, because, this time,
I had skimped a bit on the costs, and my steed wasn't of the highest grade.
Anyway, had it been a matter of speed...
...So I said to him: "Do you take me for a bank or what?"
"This shovel isn't even worth the earth that soils it!"
"You think you can scam me, kiddo, but I wouldn't put Kamas on it."
With a man of my rank... it was a bold move. And in such cases, there's only one solution: you don't let go of anything!
I look him straight in the eyes and I say to him: "See, in this world there's two kinds of people, my friend:
those who pay, and those who get paid!"
Hey! Hey!
"You pay!"
Hands off my Eva!
Who are you? What are you doing in my room?
We told you so: not gonna work. We've already tried everything to get him out of there.
Yeah... Hope is just an illusion. And we stopped having illusions long ago.
By the way, what are these critters?
We don't know. They were here when we arrived.
If they could talk, they could tell us what really happened.
They're really funny.
Yes...
Without them, I think I would've lost all hope.
You're right! There's always hope.
We'll start over again from the beginning. Here's what we're gonna do...
What's your name, stranger?
Alia, my name is--
Help! Somebody!
Oh no! Someone's being attacked! Quick! Let's go check!
I'll handle him. Take care of the fountain!
Bubulle!
That's Bubulle, one of the villagers that disappeared!
Huh? What happened? Did anyone see anything?
The gemstones, at the bottom of the fountain, take them all out of the water, quickly!
It's working!
I've... understood... your... intentions... it's... the fountain... you're after!
No, you must not get near the fountain!
What the...
The water serpent, I remember it. We're doomed!
Bordegann, no!
Yugo!
You have to strike the fountain! Now! With full power!
It's too beautiful!
I don't remember a thing.
It's as if I was asleep all this time.
I... I don't know how to thank you.
Seeing you two reunited is enough.
You reminded me of what it means to be a "hero".
You know you're pretty nice as a zeroine.
Heroes are there to make the world a nicer place, aren't they?